# Ачако Номма

Chicago, IL 60647 hommaaya@hotmail.com 312.882.1172 www.linkedin.com/in/ayakohomma https://ahomma045.github.io/ https://github.com/ahomma045 public.tableau.com/app/profile/ayako.homma

# DATA SCIENCE, ANALYTICS & VISUALIZATION EXPERT

# Analyze Data and Deliver Meaningful Insights / Influence Key Business Decision Making

Experienced in market and consumer research and data analytics in apparel, footwear, travel and hospitality, retail, and consumer packaged goods (CPG) industries. Proficient in a broad range of qualitative and quantitative research methodologies and market intelligence sources across domestic and international markets. Recently completed a full-time Data Science Immersive Bootcamp Program, enhancing my ability to draw meaningful conclusions from large datasets and influence decision-makers.

## Expertise:

Analytics | Data Science | Machine Learning | Market Research | Data Mining | Forecasting | Trend Identification |
Statistical Reporting | Presentation | Data Visualization | Predictive Analytics | Business Insights | Market Intelligence |
Storytelling | Market Data | Consumer Surveys | Data Management | Python | SQL | Tableau | Excel | CPG & Retail |

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### WOLVERINE WORLD WIDE, INC., (Remote) Chicago, IL

2021 - 2022

# Senior Manager, Advanced Concepts & Trends

Led and executed domestic and international market trend research, to provide holistic view of consumer and identify whitespace opportunities. Conducted fashion trend forecasting based on most recently observed data and created predictions. Managed contracts and relationships with trend research agencies.

- Created and delivered 50-100 pages macro trend book on bi-annual basis focusing on key trends related to sustainability, digitalization, health and wellness, diversity and inclusion and retail experiences. Hosted bi-annual webinar to 300 employees, educating and increasing knowledge about industry's current state and outlook.
- Delivered monthly and quarterly updates of key trends reporting, encouraging brands and corporate to stay up to speed on latest industry's trends and react quickly.
- Presented market trends data and analysis to the international business team, assessing market performance and identifying international market opportunities.
- Presented trend forecasting during brands' ideation meetings, providing product designers and marketing teams with insights that helped them design products and plan marketing campaigns.
- Partnered with external research agencies and facilitated monthly virtual sessions, providing interactive trend learning events within the organization.

### **EUROMONITOR INTERNATIONAL**, Chicago, IL

2012 - 2021

### Senior Research Consultant 2018 - 2021

Produced data-led regional and global reports. Published a variety of opinion pieces and podcasts and was recognized as an industry expert. Delivered presentations on global industry outlook for sportswear to industry leaders and investors at UBS.

- Utilized Tableau to develop visually compelling charts and published strategic reports on economic and industry trends, competitive landscape, and growth opportunities. Produced some of the most-viewed content in Euromonitor's fashion research.
- Spoke to 100 attendees at Jewelers of America's National Convention and discussed how to be successful in the face of changing consumer behavior in the jewelry market.
- Comments and insights were cited in media including Financial Times, The Wall Street Journal, CNBC, CNN, Bloomberg, Business Insider, Fortune, Vogue, Business of Fashion, Retail Dive and Footwear News.
- Completed 3 months of internal secondment with survey / consumer insights team, increasing use of internal survey data into research reports and enhancing collaborative work between syndicated research team and survey team.

AYAKO HOMMA hommaaya@hotmail.com PAGE Two

### **EUROMONITOR INTERNATIONAL** (Continued)

# Senior Research Analyst, Chicago, IL

2015 - 2018

Developed research training sessions and supported onboarding of new team members and junior analysts. Created and delivered presentations at client's meetings, business conferences, and trade shows. Directly responded to queries and presented insights to key clients.

- Created material, trained, and presented information in excel to 20 new contractors and junior analysts worldwide bi-annually on complex research methodologies and techniques, showing how to organize, summarize and analyze data.
- Demonstrated way to incorporate web scraping into research process to research teams, improving efficiency of research process across teams.
- Spoke about luxury market performance at Luxury Interactive and served as moderator and speaker at LUXEPACK NYC and LUXEPACK LA.

#### Research Analyst, Chicago, IL

2014 - 2015

Conducted Japanese and U.S. market research, covering apparel and footwear, luxury goods, personal accessories and eyewear, and consumer health. Built and delivered annual updates of data analysis and wrote reports on market performance, market sizes, company and brand shares and channel distribution.

- Conducted primary and secondary research processes and unique research techniques such as web scraping and consumer surveys, providing additional sets of data and further supporting analysis.
- Built and enhanced relationships with key clients by responding to queries and presenting latest research findings, meeting client research requests.

### Research Analyst, Tokyo, Japan

2012 - 2014

Conducted Japanese market research on apparel and footwear, luxury goods, personal accessories and eyewear, toys and games, travel and tourism and packaging industries. Analyzed, validated, and published annual updates of datasets on market sizes, company and brand shares and channel distributions. Delivered written reports on market performance, consumer lifestyle trends, profiles of leading companies and brands.

 Published podcasts and videocasts in Japanese and English, using external communication platforms and sharing industry trends and prospects, Comments were quoted in media including the Wall Street Journal, CNBC, Nikkei Sangyo, TTG Asia, Women's Wear Daily.

#### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

HYATT INTERNATIONAL, Dubai, United Arab Emirates, Events Sales Executive, Events Sales Coordinator NISSIN TRAVEL SERVICE (U.S.A.), INC., Dublin, OH, Sales Representative / Special Project Coordinator WALT DISNEY WORLD RESORT, Lake Buena Vista, FL, Resort Concierge (Disney College Program)

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Arts (BA)**, Hospitality Business, Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI Certification, Data Science with SQL and Tableau, Cornell University, Online Program Certification, Data Science Immersive Program, General Assembly, Online Program

# Publications / Awards & Honors

"<u>The Oxford Handbook of Luxury Business</u>", Oxford Handbooks, Contributor Person Of the Month Award, Euromonitor International, for winning back a key lost client

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: English and Japanese Programming Languages: Python, SQL

Computer Skills: MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, OneNote), Tableau, SPSS, Qualtrics

# **A**DDENDUM TO **R**ESUME

# **DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS**

### **Sumo Wrestling Match Predictor**

Apr 2023

- Developed a machine learning model to predict the outcome of sumo wrestling matches with an accuracy score of at least 0.75.
- Tested various models, including KNN, SVM, decision tree, naive bayes, logistic regression, ada boost, extra trees, random forest, ridge, linear, gradient boosting
- Created a Tableau dashboard to visualize the data and predictions, providing insights into the key factors that contribute to a wrestler's success or failure.

## **Music Genre Classification**

Mar 2023

- Developed an accurate and scalable music genre classification model using feature extraction techniques and machine learning algorithms, with the goal of integrating it into Spotify's music recommendation system.
- Tested multiple models, including logistic regression, convolutional neural network (CNN), and dense neural network (DNN).

**Reddit NLP Classifier** 

Mar 2023

- Developed a machine learning model using Natural Language Processing (NLP) techniques to accurately classify posts from two fashion-related subreddits with a test accuracy of at least 0.8.
- Used four different techniques, including logistic regression and Multinomial NB, along with Count Vectorizer and TF-IDF Vectorizer.

### **Sample Constraint - Income Predictor**

Mar 2023

- Developed a machine learning model to predict whether an individual's income exceeds \$50,000 per year using a constrained sample dataset.
- Used multiple models, including logistic regression, K-Nearest Neighbors (KNN), and Support Vector Classification (SVC).

### **Ames IA Home Price Prediction**

Feb 2023

- Conducted a comprehensive analysis of the factors that influence the market value of homes in Ames, IA.
- Developed a robust model that accurately predicts home prices with an R-squared score of at least 0.8 using linear regression, Lasso, and Ridge.

#### California ACT & SAT Analysis

Feb 2023

- Analyzed California Department of Education and College Board data to identify the California counties with the lowest performance on the SAT and ACT exams and determine which subject areas require the most attention to improve student performance.
- Incorporated external data from the US Census to consider income levels of each county and provide recommendations to the state government on how to allocate additional resources to these low-performing counties.
- Utilized Tableau to create charts showing the geographic coverage of the ACT and SAT score performances in California.